《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
但你是我唯一的血亲  奥斯瓦尔德
But you are my only true blood relative, Oswald.
那只害虫必须走
That vermin has to go.
但我们要怎么说服他离开
But how can we persuade him to go?
老鼠要怎么除掉呢
How do you get rid of rats?
他喝了那个吗
Did he... did he drink that?
-是啊  -为什么
- Yes. - Why? Why?
他不该喝的
He's not supposed to.
不
No!
终于醒了
Awake at last.
你好啊  亲爱的
Well, hello, dear.
谁去叫斯特兰奇教授
Someone call Professor Strange.
你的小诡计我们走着瞧  吉姆·戈登
We'll see about your clever little plan, Jim Gordon.
我自己也能想计策
I can make plans of my own.
你好  平克尼警官
Hello, Officer Pinkney.
我能进去吗
Can I come in?
好啊
Sure.
凶器是一根撬棒
Murder weapon was a crowbar.
上面有你的指纹
Your fingerprints were on it.
我被人陷害了
I was set up!
被判犯下谋杀罪有其坏处
Being convicted for murder has its downsides.
见到你很高兴  哈维
It's good to see you, Harv.
不要放弃希望
Don't give up hope.
你怎么在这儿
What the hell are you doing here?
你觉得我们是在做什么
What's it look like we're doing?
我们要把你弄出去  来吧  走吧
We're getting you out of here. Come on, let's go.
得先洗清我的罪名
I have to clear my name.
那我就得回哥谭
To do that, I have to go back to Gotham.
仅供学习  禁止商用  更多影视
登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
你们两个小混蛋
You little punks!
翻译 小胖纸Amy   Silence   DustD   charcie   大K   小酸奶!
把包放下
Don't you take that bag!
知道你们偷的是谁的东西吗
You have any idea who you're stealing from?
翻译 草草   时间轴 风吹来的那片云
别管了
Leave it!
校对&总监 草草   后期 饿得慌
那是我的钱
That's my money.
是你偷来的
You stole it.
现在你也被偷了  蠢蛋
Now you got stole, chump.
我抓到你们  你们就死定了
I catch you, you're dead!
你们俩都是
Both of you.
还有  你真不会当坏蛋
By the way, you're a terrible crook.
被两个孩子抢了
Letting two kids rob you.
这钱你真不配拿
You really don't deserve this money.
你在干什么  小混蛋
What the hell you doing, you little freak?!
你在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
你们俩都死定了
You're both dead!
你们最好都别碰我的钱
Nobody ever better touch my money!
我不是小偷
I'm not a thief.
我不是为钱而行窃的
I don't steal for the money.
这是研究  我要想了解哥谭
This is research. I can't understand Gotham
-就必须了解这儿的罪犯  -听着
- until I understand its criminals. - Look,
你要了解罪犯的那套
okay, this whole understanding criminals thing
要惹毛我了
is getting on my nerves.
你扔掉的是你那半的钱
That was your half you threw out!
我还留了够买汉堡的钱
I saved enough for burgers.
哥谭今天处于高度警戒状态
Gotham is on high alert today
前哥谭市警局警探  已定罪杀人犯
after former GCPD Detective and convicted murderer
詹姆斯·戈登越狱了...
James Gordon escaped...
布洛克警探  你听说了吗
Detective Bullock, have you heard the news?
我听说了  爱德
Yeah, Ed, I heard.
你觉得他会做什么
So, what do you think he'll do?
我了解吉姆·戈登
Knowing Jim Gordon,
他不找到那个陷害了他的混蛋
I'd say he's not gonna rest until he finds the son of a bitch
是不会善罢甘休的
who framed him for murder.
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
布洛克
Bullock!
这是你唯一的机会
This is your one and only chance.
告诉我他在哪里
You tell me where he is.
我起誓我不知道  警监
Hand to God, Cap. I have no idea.
得了吧
Oh, stop it.
你还没聪明到能在我面前装傻
You're not smart enough to play dumb.
我们都知道吉姆没杀平克尼
We both know Jim did not kill Pinkney.
我只知道法庭判他有罪
I know that a court found him guilty.
他想证明自己的清白  好啊
He wants to prove his own innocence, great.
我希望他能做到
I hope he does.
但哥谭的公众呢
The public, the people of Gotham?
我和你服务的市民呢
The ones you and I serve?
他们必须看到  知道
They have to know, they have to see
我们是公正无私的  你懂吗
that we're impartial, you understand?
哥谭市民哪凉快哪玩去吧
The people of Gotham can eat my socks.
不错啊
Nice try.
愤然离去
Walk away in a huff?
现在我知道你了解情况了
Now I know you know something.
如果你窝藏帮助吉姆·戈登
If you're providing aid and shelter to Jim Gordon,
哪怕是给他一杯水
anything-- a glass of water--
我都会毫不留情面地抓你
I will bust you like a bum I never met.
警监  我也希望我知道他的下落
Cap, I wish I knew where he was.
但我不知道
But I don't.
你走吧
Go.
没什么事吧
Everything okay?
没事  开始干活儿吧
Yeah, let's get to work.
哥谭
第二季  第十七集
这一切我已经翻来覆去想了很多遍
I've been going over and over this a thousand times in my mind,
这些案子肯定都是有联系的
it all has to be connected.
艺术博物馆失窃案
The theft at the art museum,
火车站爆炸案
the bombing at the train station,
内务处的密报
the I.A. tip-off,
平克尼的谋杀案
Pinkney's murder--
都是精心策划的陷害的一部分
it's all a part of an elaborate frame.
那么这人很聪明  谨慎
So he's smart, meticulous,
有技巧  有门路
got technical skill and access.
一名在职警察
An active cop?
一定是
Has to be.
所以撬棒放进证物室后
Only way he could have access to a crowbar
他还能拿得到
after it was put into evidence.
这并没缩小多少嫌疑人范围
That doesn't really narrow the suspect list too much.
吉姆  说老实话
I mean, come on, Jim, be honest.
跟你有过节的警察大概有五百个
You probably got 500 cops who have beef with you.
是啊  但至于陷害我杀人吗
Yeah, but enough to frame me for murder?
也许有十个吧
Maybe ten.
你得承认
You got to admit
你在树敌方面的确有那么点
you do have a little bit of a knack for, uh,
本事
making enemies.
我想的是12个
My number was 12.
主要是洛布的忠诚追随者
Mainly Loeb loyalists.
谁知道呢  也许洛布本人就是始作俑者
Who knows-- maybe Loeb himself is behind this.
你走上那条路之前
Before you go down that rabbit hole,
我以朋友的身份劝你
I got to say something to you as a friend, hmm?
你现在还可以逃
You can still run.
去个小岛  买艘香蕉船
Go to an island, buy a banana boat,
留点胡子  找到小莱  好好生活
grow a beard, find Lee, have a life.
自从你入狱  我就一直在调查这事
Look, I've been working this thing since you went away.
不是说毫无希望
And I'm not saying it's hopeless.
但是巴恩斯正在找你
But Barnes is on the hunt.
-你的时间不多  -他威胁你了吗
- You don't have much time. - He threaten you?
是我帮你越狱的  记得吗
Hey, I'm the one who busted you out of jail, remember?
我已经做了选择
I made my choice.
好吧  就算我逃走
All right, let's say I run.
找到了小莱  说服她重新接受我
I find Lee, I somehow convince her to take me back.
然后呢
What then?
我让她过逃犯的生活吗
I get her to live as a fugitive?
我必须洗清我的罪名
I have to clear my name.
否则  还不如坐牢呢
Otherwise, I might as well be in jail.
可是要怎么做
But how?
从哪开始
Starting where?
丹特曾跟我说  内务处秘密
Dent once told me I.A. secretly records
录音并存档所有来电
and archives all their incoming calls on tape.
也就是说
Which means
那个给内务处报信的目击证人
the eyewitness who called into I.A.?
他们以为是平克尼的那个
The one they assumed was Pinkney?
可能会有一卷录了他声音的带子
There could be a tape with his voice on it.
这希望可不大  兄弟
That's a hell of a long shot, brother.
而且即便  只是假设一下
And if... okay, just saying if
有这样一盘带子
a tape like that exists,
那也肯定会被层层严守
it's gonna be locked up tighter than a duck's ass
放在内务处的证物室里
in I.A. evidence.
所以说  你走运了
That's why it's lucky for you
哈维叔叔那边有人
Uncle Harvey has connections.
金尼
Ginny.
我最喜欢的内务处小甜心过得如何呀
How's my favorite I.A. Sugar plum, huh?
你觉得我为什么要打给你呀  宝贝
Well, why do you think I'm calling, baby?
听说你要结婚了
Heard you were getting married.
她改主意了
She changed her mind.
聪明的姑娘
Smart girl.
你真是头畜生  布洛克
Oh, you're an animal, Bullock,
-你知道吗  -是的  长官  我知道
- you know that? - Oh, yes, ma'am. I do, I do.
来吧  布洛克
Come on, Bullock.
好的  宝贝  我马上去
Yeah, baby. I'll be right there.
等我一秒钟
Hold on for me for a second!
一小时  从门下塞进去
An hour. Slip 'em under the door.
来啊  布洛克  我没时间老等你
Come on, Bullock! I ain't got all night!
什么都别说
Don't say a word.
爸爸来啦
Daddy's comin'!
詹姆斯·戈登
给我拿来
Give me that.
怎么了  甜心  你想干什么
Whoa, what's up, sweetheart? What are you doin', huh?
-你要去哪  -不要  救命
- Where you goin'? - No! Help!
来啊  快点  来吧
Do it! Come on, do it!
谁来救救我
Somebody help!
快点
Do it!
赶紧滚
Get out of here.
滚
Go!
女士  你没事吧
Ma'am, are you okay?
不客气
You're welcome.
举起手来  不然我打爆你的头
Hands up or I'll blow your head off.
哥谭市警局  你被逮...
GCPD. You're under...
你是吉姆·戈登
You're Jim Gordon.
听我说
Listen to me...
我是巴克利  在第五大道斯普利街
This is Barkley, over on Fifth and Spring.
我抓到了吉姆
I got Jim...
别杀我
Don't kill me!
我是无辜的  你听到了吗
I'm innocent, you hear me?
所有小组  是他妈的吉姆·戈登
All units, it's Jim freaking Gordon!
我需要支援
I need backup now!
父亲  我跟你相识才不久
Father, I only knew you a short time.
但是你出现在我独自面对
But you came to me when I was alone
这冷酷黑暗世界的时候
in this cold, dark world.
你给了我家庭
You gave me a family.
我永远不会忘记你
I'll never forget you
今生今世都...
as long as I l...
父亲啊
Oh, Father.
真是无聊
What a bore that was.
是啊  但房子现在是咱们的了
Yeah, but the house is ours now.
-而且咱们有钱了  -闭嘴
- And we're rich. - Quiet.
他是那么爱我们大家
He loved us all so much.
的确  但...奥斯瓦尔德
Indeed. But-but, Oswald,
奥斯瓦尔德...
Oswald...
虽然心情沉痛  但咱们得说点实际的
as painful as this is, we need to talk practicalities.
我是帮你叫出租车  还是你自己坐公交
Um, can I call you a cab or will you take the bus?
我不明白
I don't understand.
你不能跟我们回家了
Well, you're not returning to the house with us.
那我该去哪
But where shall I go?
除了那儿  哪都行
Anywhere but there.
奥斯瓦尔德  我很高兴你有机会跟父亲团聚
Oswald, I'm so happy that you and your father reconnected,
但他把房子和财产都留给了我
but he left the house and the estate to me.
与臭名昭著的杀人犯
And I'm-I'm simply not comfortable
同住一个屋檐下  让我不舒服
sleeping under the same roof as a notorious murderer.
但我已经不一样了
But I'm not like that anymore.
就算我想  我都伤不了一只苍蝇
I-I couldn't hurt a fly, even if I wanted to.
求你  父亲是我最后的亲人了
Please, my father was all that I had!
我流着他的血
We shared the same blood,
他希望我们大家在一起  他亲口说的
and-and he wanted us to be together. He told me.
让我留下吧  我什么都愿做
Let me stay. I'll do anything.
你的确是他的骨肉
You are his blood.
家里也的确需要帮手
We do need help around the house.
母亲
Mother.
既然有奥斯瓦尔德  何必浪费钱请佣人呢
Why waste good money on servants when we have Oswald?
我什么都愿做
I'll do anything.
先把那些恶心的花扔掉吧
You can start by getting rid of those disgusting flowers.
我一向讨厌百合
I've always detested lilies.
是  好的
Yes. Of course.
你不会真让他留下来吧
You're not really letting him stay.
他是以利亚唯一的亲骨肉
He's Elijah's only natural son.
如果他找个好律师  事情会变棘手
If he found the right lawyer, he could make things difficult.
尤其如果有人调查他父亲的死因
Especially if people look into how his father died.
那就要跟他住一起吗
So we just live with him, then?
不  先留住他
No, we keep him close,
一段时间后
and after a suitable amount of time goes by,
可怜的奥斯瓦尔德  悲痛不已
poor Oswald, overcome with grief,
便会自我了断
will take his own life.
在那之前
Till then,
现成的免费仆人嘛
we have a free servant.
我可以解雇女佣了
I can fire the maid.
我...杀了...
I... murdered my...
我父母
parents.
我割了他们的喉咙
I cut their throats.
我加入了变态杀手的帮派
I joined a gang of psychopathic killers.
我试图杀吉姆·戈登和小莱·汤普金斯
I tried to kill Jim Gordon and Lee Thompkins.
我被脑中的恶魔操控
I was a puppet of these demons in my head
他们迫使我做了这些骇人的事
and they were forcing me to do these terrible things.
我希望能回到过去  撤销我的罪孽
I wish I could go back and undo what I've done.
但我不能
Only I can't.
我不觉得自己精神不正常
I don't feel insane...
现在不了
now.
我只是
I just...
觉得很悲伤
I feel sad.
谢谢你  芭芭拉
Thank you, Barbara.
那番话很勇敢
That was very brave.
你觉得是什么让你的心理
What do you suppose made this
健康起来了
healthful change in you?
也许我只是
Maybe I just...
需要好好睡一觉
really needed some sleep.
演得不错
It's a good act.
你确定她是在演戏  对吧
You're so sure it's an act, are you?
你不觉得吗
Aren't you?
我不知道
I have no idea.
不管怎样  她引起了我的兴趣
One way or the other, she intrigues me.
如果你允许我们对她使用严酷的释梦治疗
Well, if you would allow us to apply rigorous dream therapy,
就能确切地知道了
we would know, for sure.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no.
我们的疗法确实很出色  皮博迪女士
We do have a very useful hammer, Ms. Peabody,
但不适用于所有病人
but not all of our patients are nails.
谢谢
Thank you.
昨晚到底发生什么了
What the hell happened last night?
碰到抢劫了
Stumbled onto a mugging.
吉姆·戈登非得见义勇为
And Jim Gordon couldn't just walk by.
你在哪睡的
Where'd you sleep?
没睡  就到处溜达
I didn't. Just walked around.
-巴恩斯怎么样了  -他大发雷霆
- How's Barnes? - He's on the warpath.
州长悬赏了一万赏金
Governor announced a $10,000 reward
要捉拿你
for anyone who helps catch you.
一万吗  你该抓我回去
$10,000? You should turn me in.
如果赏金翻到两万  我会考虑的
If he doubled it to 20, I'd give it some thought.
好  听吧
Okay, here.
内务处
Internal Affairs.
我想举报犯罪
I... I want to report a crime.
认出这声音了吗
You recognize that voice?
感觉经过了变声处理
Sounds like it's been disguised.
我看到詹姆斯·戈登警探
I saw Detective James Gordon
打死了西奥·盖勒文市长
shooting Mayor Theo Galavan
就在南码头那里
on the south side docks.
企鹅当时在用球棒打他
The Penguin was beating him with a bat,
但是戈登最终扣了扳机
but it was Gordon that pulled the trigger.
是鸟叫吗
Was that a bird?
再回放一次
Run it back.
不是
Nah.
我们得找人处理一下这段录音
We gotta find somebody to clean up the tape.
将背景分离出来
Isolate the sound,
还原一下人声之类的
maybe do something to the voice.
我得走了
I gotta get going.
巴恩斯盯我盯得死死的
Barnes is watching me like a hawk.
好吧
All right.
你作为搭档已经很够意思了
You've done more than any partner could ask.
从现在开始
From now on,
离我远一点
stay away from me.
为了你自己好
For your own sake.
如果洛布也有份
If Loeb is behind this,
你最好别掺和进来
you don't want to be mixed up in it.
你打算怎么办
What are you gonna do?
我还有几个能求助的朋友
I still have some friends I could ask for help.
你要去哪
Where you going?
吉姆
Jim!
你好  爱德
Hi, Ed.
求求你  求求你不要伤害我
Please... please, don't hurt me.
放松  我不会伤害你
Relax, I'm not gonna hurt you.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
-我的帮助  -我没有杀平克尼
- My help? - I didn't kill Pinkney.
你得相信我
You have to believe me.
我信
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
我得查出是谁陷害我的
I need to find the man who framed me.
不管是谁  他都掩盖得很好
Whoever it was, he covered his tracks well.
但我有发现
But I have something.
他第一次打电话给内务处时的录音
A recording of his first call to I.A.
内务处会秘密录下所有来电
I.A. secretly records everyone who calls in.
是吗
They do?
真是一群狡猾的家伙
They're sneaky little buggers.
那你听到了什么
Uh, and what did, what did you hear?
如果你不介意我问的话
If you don't mind my asking.
没什么发现  他变了声
Not much. He disguised his voice.
但是录音中还有别的声音
But there are other sounds on the tape.
你是搞音频的
I figure you work with audio.
我希望你能帮帮我
I was hoping you could help me.
吉姆...
Jim...
朋友...
my friend...
你是来对地方了
you've come to the right place.
请坐
Please, have a seat.
我去拿我的工具
I will get my stuff
再泡点茶
and make some tea.
我们还是祈祷海尔加还没有另谋高就吧
Well, let's pray Helga hasn't signed on anywhere new yet.
这是我的家传菜谱
It's a family recipe.
很遗憾你不喜欢
I'm sorry you don't like it.
相信我的厨艺会慢慢精进的
I'm sure my cooking will improve over time.
没那么糟
It's not that bad.
明天  你要去一趟肉店
Tomorrow, you need to go to the butcher.
周日晚餐  我想要美味的烤肉
I'd like a nice roast for Sunday dinner.
而不是你的...
Not your...
荡妇老妈的菜炖牛肉
slut mother's goulash.
美味的烤肉
A nice roast.
好的  女士
Yes, ma'am.
今晚把这些收拾干净
Oh, and clean up this mess tonight.
我可见不得脏盘子
I can't stand the sight of dirty dishes.
真准  查尔斯
Good shot, Charles.
我还得收拾盘子呢
I must get to these dishes.
但这个真好玩
But this-this has been delightful, really.
是啊  听上去是像鸟的声音
Yes, it does sound like a bird.
他尽力伪装了自己的声音
And he's doing his best to mask his voice.
可惜录音质量这么差
Too bad the quality's so poor.
好吧
Ah, well,
恐怕没别的办法了
I'm afraid it's a dead end.
我们至少该清清带子
We should at least clean the tape.
好吧
Right.
你得再来点茶
You need some more tea.
那个杀了平克尼并陷害你的人
So the person who killed Pinkney and framed you
也是袭击了艺术品博物馆的人
is the same person that attacked the art museum
还在火车站放了炸弹
and planted the bomb in the train station.
难以置信
Amazing.
你毫无线索吗
And you don't have any leads?
我觉得是洛布在搞鬼
I think Loeb was behind it.
报复
Payback.
他在哥谭市警局还有走狗
He still has lackeys in the GCPD.
是吗
Is that so?
一切都表明是一个警察干的
Everything points to a cop.
要么就是跟警察合作  有门路的人
Or someone who worked with the police, had access.
你没事吧  爱德
You all right, Ed?
好得很
Right as rain.
就是在想
Just thinking.
你总不会认为是洛布亲手杀了平克尼吧
Surely, you don't think that Loeb killed Pinkney himself?
不
No.
他找了个疯子替他下手
He had some psychopath do it for him.
疯子这词太过了吧
Psychopath seems a strong word.
他冷血地用撬棒把一个人活活打死
He bludgeoned a man to death with a crowbar in cold blood.
他有病
He's sick.
你虽这么说
You say that, yet...
但你也杀过很多人吧
you've killed lots of people, haven't you?
那是执行公务
That was in the line of duty.
而冷血杀人的人就是疯子
And a person who would kill in cold blood is a psychopath.
我...
See, I...
我就知道传言不是真的
I knew the rumors weren't true.
什么传言
What rumors?
关于你杀了盖勒文
About you killing Galavan.
你绝不会那么做的
You would never do that.
那你不就像你在找的人一样了吗
That would make you like the people that you're hunting--
有病
sick...
不正常
diseased.
壶开了
Thar she blows.
闭嘴  你话太多了
Shut up, you're talking too much.
爱德
Ed,
企鹅跟你提过那晚上的事吗
did Penguin ever say anything about that night?
企鹅有跟你说过盖勒文死的那晚的事吗
Did Penguin ever tell you anything about the night that Galavan died?
没有  记得吗  那段友谊我早早结束了
No. Remember, I nipped that friendship in the bud.
巴恩斯把他抓回哥谭市警局后
And you didn't talk to him in the GCPD,
你也没在那儿跟他说过话
when Barnes brought him in?
是的  没有
Yes. No.
我...就打了个招呼
I... just to say hi.
带子清好了
Oh, tape's finished.
我再听听看
I'm going to give that a listen.
我们一起听吧
Let's both listen.
好主意
Swell idea.
内务处
Internal Affairs.
我想举报犯罪
I... I want to report a crime.
我看到詹姆斯·戈登警探
I saw Detective James Gordon
打死了西奥·盖勒文市长
shooting Mayor Theo Galavan
就在南码头那里
on the south side docks.
企鹅当时在用球棒打他
The Penguin was beating him with a bat,
但是戈登最终扣了扳机
but it was Gordon that pulled the trigger.
不是鸟
It's not a bird.
是机械
It was mechanical.
没有手指  我却可以指
Without fingers I point,
没有手臂  我却可以敲[报时]
without arms I strike,
没有脚丫  我却可以走  我是什么
without feet I run. What am I?
你是钟
You're a clock.
正确
Correct.
我知道是你  爱德
I know it was you, Ed.
我
Me?
你
You.
你猜怎么着
Guess what.
我知道你知道是我了
I knew that you knew that I knew.
所以你的椅子被连到电源上了
That's why your chair was wired to the mains.
*走过步道  进入小巷*
*Over the pavement and down the alley*
*这寒风如此彻骨*
*Oh, my, this wind is cold*
*冻得我脚也疼  鼻子也疼*
*It bites my toes and nips my nose*
*我们一步一步往前走*
*As over the ground we go.*
希望你喜欢户外  吉姆
I hope you like the outdoors, Jimbo.
我知道个好地方
I know just the spot.
出来  出来  不管你在哪
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
你肯定在想
I bet you're wondering...
"爱德为什么要这么对我"
"Why would Ed do this to me?"
"陷害我"
"Set me up."
"毁掉我的人生"
"Ruin my life."
我提示你一下  吉姆
I'll give you a hint, Jimbo.
KK
K.K.
柯丽丝汀·柯林格
Kristen Kringle.
该死
Rats.
你看到我的外套了吗
Have you seen my jacket?
外面冷死了
It's freezing outside.
抱歉
Sorry.
我拿去补袖子了
I was fixing the sleeve.
你给撕破了
You'd ripped it.
你会缝衣服
You know how to sew?
阿尔弗雷德说这对年轻单身汉来说是重要技能
Alfred says it's an important skill for young bachelors.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
搞什么
What the...
戈登警探
Detective Gordon?
布鲁斯
Bruce?
你怎么在这儿
What are you doing here?
我还想问你呢
I could ask the same about you.
我找到了陷害我的人  他...
I found the man who framed me. He....
我需要电话...
I need a phon...
太好了  我家里还来了个死警察
Great, a dead cop in my crib now.
别忘记放樱桃  奥斯瓦尔德
Don't forget the cherries, Oswald.
对了
Oh, right.
樱桃  樱桃
Cherries, cherries, cherries, cherries.
奥斯瓦尔德
Oswald.
我的酒呢
My drink?
对不起  没有樱桃了
I'm sorry, there's no cherries.
没有樱桃了
No cherries?
下次我再要樱桃
The next time I ask for cherries,
你最好准备好
there'd better be cherries.
是  格蕾丝  夫人  好的
Yes, Grace... ma'am. Of course.
母亲叫我提醒你明天晚饭的事
Mother said to remind you of tomorrow's dinner.
他是怎么了
What's wrong with him?
谁知道
Who knows?
母亲要烤肉
Mother wants a roast.
这次烤好点
And make it good this time.
当然  我会的
Yes, I will.
还睡着呢
Still sleeping.
对他来说最好了
Best thing for him.
多谢你随叫随到  阿尔弗雷德
Thank you for coming when I called, Alfred.
我当然会去了
Course I came.
毫无疑问
No question.
你瘦了
You're looking thin.
我吃的挺饱的
I'm getting plenty to eat.
这我深表怀疑  布鲁斯少爷
That I very much doubt, Master Bruce.
但有些事我们得谈谈
But there're things that we must discuss.
我不会回来的
I'm not coming back.
我明白  但是
I understand that, but...
-现在还不行  -我们得谈谈
- Not yet. - We need to talk.
-阿尔弗雷德  -早上好
- Alfred... - Good morning.
戈登警探  你起来真的好吗
Detective Gordon, should you be up?
我没事  你给我处理了伤口
I'm fine. You stitched me up.
其实  是布鲁斯少爷做的
Actually, it was Master Bruce.
你昏倒后  他从塞琳娜·凯尔家给我打来了电话
He called from Selina Kyle's when you passed out,
所以我就把你带来了这儿
so I thought, bring you here.
对你来说最安全的地方
Safest place for you.
布鲁斯少爷  你能不能去
Master Bruce, I wonder if you might go
洗衣室把警探的衣服拿来  拜托
and get the detective his clothes from the laundry room. Please.
你没事我很高兴
I'm glad you're okay.
我给你做点早餐  坐吧
So I'll make you some breakfast. Take a seat.
要咖啡吗
Like some coffee?
好的  谢谢
Yes, please.
给
There we go.
布鲁斯跟塞琳娜·凯尔一起住多久了
How long has Bruce been living with Selina Kyle?
"火柴"马龙那件事之后开始的
Ever since the Matches Malone debacle.
原来盯着杀死你父母的人
Turns out staring into the cold, dead eyes of the man
冰冷无生气的双眼
that killed your parents
也不能让你了却心事
doesn't bring the right amount of closure.
布鲁斯就不该走进那个房间
Bruce never should've been in that room.
我该先找到马龙的
I should've gotten to Malone first.
是啊  可不是嘛
Yes, you should have done.
但你没有  不是吗
But you didn't, did you?
煎好的鸡蛋不能恢复
You can't unfry an egg,
我老妈以前经常这么说
as my dear old mum used to say.
我们先不说布鲁斯少爷的事了
So why don't we leave Master Bruce's situation alone
谈谈你的事吧
and why don't we discuss yours.
说来话长
It's a long story.
嗯  你被陷害杀了了
Right, so you were framed for the murder
那名警官
of that other police officer.
你越了狱  然后找到了
You escaped from prison, you then tracked down
陷害你的人  结果被人打中了腿
the man that framed you and you were promptly shot in the leg.
嗯  那么回答我  警探
Right, so, answer me this, Detective.
你是否知道
Do you have any idea
要如何摆脱
how you're gonna get out of this
这可怕的困境
awful pickle?
我知道
Yes, I do.
阿卡姆疯人院
来吧  亲爱的  你的未来在等待
Come, my dear. Your future awaits.
你确定吗
You're sure?
我经营的是医院  不是监狱
I run a hospital, not a prison.
你已经正常了
You're sane.
继续关着你  不合法律也不道德
It would be unethical and illegal to keep you confined.
-如果我...  -别说了
- What if I... - Hush, now.
生活充满不确定
Life is full of uncertainty.
如果真出了什么事  我们永远在这儿
And if something does happen, we're always here.
去吧
Off you go.
如果你总这么随随便便地放走疯子
If you keep releasing lunatics so liberally,
你会招来骂名的
you're going to get a bad reputation.
我才不要什么好名声
I'm not looking for a good reputation.
我们释放芭芭拉·基恩
We're releasing Barbara Kean into the wild
是为了观察她的行为
to observe her behavior.
她是个美丽的实验
She's a beautiful experiment.
你知道她会做什么  是吧
You know what she's going to do, don't you?
其实  我不知道
I don't, actually.
但我知道  会很有趣的
But I do know it will be interesting.
尼格玛说对了一件事
Nygma was right about one thing.
我不能直接去找警察
I can't just go to the cops.
他们绝不会相信我
They'll never believe me.
我需要切实证据
I need hard proof.
警察啊  都是混蛋
Cops, right? Jerks.
尼格玛说他跟企鹅是在林子里初遇的
Nygma said he met Penguin for the first time in the woods.
他女友就是在那个时间左右失踪的
That's right around the same time his girlfriend went missing.
我觉得他当时是去埋她了
I think he was burying her.
就像他本打算把我也埋了
Just like he was going to bury me.
怎么  你想找到她的尸体
What, you want to find her body?
有点大海捞针吧
Touch of the old needle in a haystack, innit?
尼格玛知道她在哪
Nygma knows where she is.
怎么  你觉得他会直接告诉你吗
What, and you think he's gonna, what, straight tell you?
他就是会告诉我
That's exactly what he's gonna do.
但我需要帮助
But I need help.
你尽管说
Whatever we can do.
谢谢
Thanks.
但我需要一个巴恩斯确信会背叛我的人
But I need someone Barnes knows will betray me.
干什么
What?
我找谁谈领取吉姆·戈登的悬赏
Who do I talk to about the reward for Jim Gordon?
过来  过来
Come here, come here.
-放开我  -过来
- Let go of me. - Come here, come here.
我是来领悬赏的
I'm here for my reward.
我给你奖赏
I'll give you a reward.
布洛克
Bullock!
你见到吉姆·戈登了吗
Have you seen Jim Gordon?
看情况了
Depends.
真有一万块奖金吗
There really ten grand?
要看你的情报准不准了
Depends on your information.
他几小时前去了我家
He was at my place a couple hours ago.
他中了枪
He'd been shot.
中枪  谁打了他
Shot? Who shot him?
没说  他胡言乱语的
Didn't say. He wasn't making a lot of sense.
他还在吗
Is he still there now?
不  他走了  我不知道去哪了
No, he took off. I don't know where,
但他大概去找地方躲起来了
but he was just looking for a place to lie low for a while, I guess.
这情报不值一万
That's not worth $10,000.
好吧
Fine.
他走之前  他说他知道企鹅藏在哪了
Before he left he said he'd found out where The Penguin was hiding,
他要去找他
he was gonna go see him.
他去找企鹅做什么
Why would he go see The Penguin?
我不知道
I don't know.
说是企鹅知道尸体藏在哪
Something about Penguin knows where the body's buried?
什么尸体
What bodies?
-我不知道  -企鹅现在在哪
- I don't know. - Where's The Penguin now?
没人知道
No one knows.
你到底给不给我钱
You gonna pay me or what?
不给怎么样
Or what.
放松  放松
Relax, relax.
或许戈登找不到企鹅
Maybe Gordon won't even find Penguin.
你个白痴  他是个警探
You idiot. He's a detective.
他是专门找人的
He finds people for a living!
企鹅不会告诉他的
Penguin won't tell him.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
我骗谁呢
Who am I kidding?
你个蠢货
You stupid...
蠢货  蠢货
Stupid, stupid!
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
好了  想想  爱德  好好想想
Okay, calculate, Ed, calculate.
戈登找到企鹅的几率有多大
Chances of Gordon finding Penguin?
就算80%
Say 80%.
企鹅告诉戈登的几率呢
Chances of Penguin telling Gordon?
也是80%吧
Also 80%.
那么戈登有60%的可能会找到柯丽丝汀
So it's a 60% chance of Gordon finding Kristen.
好吧
That settles it.
你好  柯丽丝汀
Hello, Kristin.
我知道  没想到还会再见到我吧
I know, didn't expect to see me again,
但是  没办法啊
but... circumstances.
我恐怕得转移你了
Now, I'm afraid I'm gonna have to move you.
吉姆·戈登
Jim Gordon.
你找到企鹅了啊
So you did find Penguin.
那只小鸟也泄密了
And that little bird sang.
不  我是跟踪你来的
No, I just followed you.
你是有意向那个小坏蛋泄露消息
You fed information to that little miscreant,
因为猜到我会听说
assuming that I'd hear.
不不不
Or, no. No, no, no.
当然了  你们是串通好的
Of course, you were in cahoots.
你们当然是串通好的
Of course you were in cahoots.
不管怎样  干得漂亮  吉姆
Well, either way, bravo, Jim.
我真想鼓掌  但你的枪在我手里
I'd clap, but I have your gun in my hand.
怎么会这样
How did this happen to you?
你怎么会变成这样
How did you become this?
你个傻瓜
You dummy.
这才是我的本性
This is who I am.
我只是终于面对真相了
It was just finally admitting the truth to myself.
再加上还杀了几个人
Well, that and murdering some people.
我不信
I don't believe that.
你不信  为什么  吉姆
You don't believe it. Why, Jim?
因为那样你就显得无能吗
'Cause it would make you incompetent
我其实一直就在你的眼皮底下
to know that I was right under your nose the whole time?
还是你不想承认我们内心都有个恶魔
Or you don't want to admit that there's a monster in all of us?
因为你  是最该清楚这一点的
Because you, of all people, should know that!
所以嫁祸你才那么容易
That's what made it so easy to frame you!
我是你的朋友
I was your friend.
是吗  吉姆  你是我的朋友吗
Were you, Jim? Were you my friend?
还是你只是可怜我
Or did you just pity me?
可怜怪异的爱德啊
Oh, poor, weird little Ed
他傻乎乎地玩文字游戏  打谜语
with his little silly wordplay and his little riddles.
-你完全是疯了  -是啊
- You're completely insane. - Yeah.
你那么想或许更轻松一些
It's probably easier for you to think that.
冲着老交情  我们再猜一则谜语吧
How about one last riddle for old time's sake?
有些人的噩梦
A nightmare for some.
有些人的救世主
For others, a savior, I come.
我的手冰冷而绝望
My hands, cold and bleak,
伸向那颗温暖的心
it's the warm hearts they seek.
死亡
Death.
又对了
Right again.
再见了  吉姆
Good-bye, Jim.
放下枪
Drop the gun.
放下
Drop it!
巴恩斯警监  我在..
Captain Barnes, I was... I...
我在逮捕吉姆
I'm arresting Jim.
够了  爱德
Stop it, Ed.
我们都听到了
We heard everything.
放下枪  跪在地上
Now drop the gun and get on your knees!
不  这是...
No, this is... This... I...
他是...
He's-he's...
最后的机会
Last chance!
该死
Oh, crud.
怎么样
How is it?
不会太腥吧
Not too gamey?
太老了
Overcooked.
尝尝另一块腿肉吧
Try the other joint.
嫩多了
It is much more tender.
还是一样
It's the same.
但还是比我荡妇老妈的菜炖牛肉强吧
Still, beats my slut mother's goulash, no?
孩子们呢  再按一次铃
Where are the children? Ring the bell again.
他们恐怕听不见的
I doubt they'll hear it.
你看上去不太一样了
You look different.
你注意到了
You noticed.
是啊
Yes.
我换发型了
I'm doing my hair a different way, so...
查尔斯  萨莎
Charles! Sasha!
他们哪去了
Where are they?
我找到了雪莉酒瓶  格蕾丝
I found the sherry decanter, Grace.
就是你下了毒  用来杀我父亲的那瓶
The one with poison in it that you used to kill my father.
你在说什么
What on earth are you talking about?
你该立刻倒掉的
You should have thrown it away!
看来你太小气了  都不肯浪费好毒药
Guess you're a little too mean to waste good poison, huh?
别走
Don't go.
查尔斯  萨莎  救命
Charles! Sasha! Help!
-他们不会来的  -他们在哪
- They won't come. - Where are they?
你以为他俩的味道是一样的
You thought they tasted the same,
但萨莎
but Sasha...
-不不  -绝对要更嫩一些
- No. No. No. - Definitely more tender.
-不  -至少在我看来
- No! - In my opinion.
不  不
No. No!
你说你是无辜的  你的确是
You said you were innocent, and you were.
我很庆幸
I'm glad.
看来我该向你道歉
I guess I owe you an apology.
不  你只是在尽职
No. You were doing your duty.
我不能为此怪你
Can't fault you for that.
嗯  我还是欠你个人情
Yeah, well, I owe you one.
不必  但我也接受了
Oh, not necessary, but I'll take it.
能不能帮个忙
Can you do me a favor
别太责怪布洛克
and take it easy on Bullock?
谢谢
Thanks.
那么  你什么时候回来工作
So... when are you coming back to work?
我不会回来了
I'm not coming back.
至少暂时还不能
Not yet anyhow.
是吗
No?
我有件事得先去做
There's something I have to do first.
小莱·汤普金斯的号码
Lee Thompkins' number.
她在南方一个法医部门工作
She's working for an ME department down south.
我答应布鲁斯·韦恩会解决他父母的案子
I promised Bruce Wayne I'd solve his parents' murder.
我得先做那个
I have to do that first.
然后我就自由了
Then I'm free.
韦恩案已经结了  吉姆
The Wayne case is closed, Jim.
犯人死了
The perp is dead.
但是谁雇了他  为什么  我得查明白
But who hired him? Why? I need to find out.
有时候  真相就是无从查明
Sometimes we never find out. It happens.
我需要你给我韦恩案的案卷
I need you to give me the Wayne files.
你拿走这个  我就给你韦恩案案卷
You take this, and I'll give you the Wayne files.
打给她
Call her.
我去拿
I'll go get 'em.
跟你做了什么或没做什么无关  阿尔弗雷德
It was nothing that you did or didn't do, Alfred.
我离开的原因
Why I went away.
我希望你明白这点
I want you to know that.
我知道
I do.
谢谢你
Thank you very much.
等塞琳娜准备好  我就跟她回城
I'll be going back to the city as soon as Selina's ready.
她在洗澡
She's just taking a hot shower.
你知道卢修斯·福克斯先生几天前
You do know that Mr. Lucius Fox fixed your old man's computer
修好了你爸的电脑吧
a couple of days ago, don't you?
你打算什么时候告诉我啊  阿尔弗雷德
And when were you going to tell me, Alfred?
我今早就想告诉你的
Well, I tried telling you this morning.
我现在不也说了吗
I'm telling you again now, aren't I?
你干什么
What are you doing?
她随时会进来  我们商量一下吧
She could walk in here. Have a word?
-我信任她  -不是信不信任的问题
- I trust her. - It's not about trust, is it?
不管你父亲在做什么
Whatever your father was doing,
他对外隐瞒是有原因的
he did it in secret for a reason,
为了保护他所爱的人
to protect those he loved.
这跟我对那小姑娘的看法无关
Doesn't matter about my personal opinion about that young girl,
但她对你一直很够意思
but she has been a bloody good friend to you,
很忠诚
and she's been loyal.
所以  你可以
So, you know, you go ahead,
继承你父亲的遗志  这我不能阻拦
continue your father's work. I can't stop you, man.
我也试过了
I've tried, haven't I?
但我不能让你把那姑娘也拉入危险中
But I will not have you put that little girl's life in danger.
要么做这个  要么选她
It's either the work, or it's her.
你不能兼得  明白吗
You can't have both, do you understand?
天呐
Man!
有钱人家的水压真好
Rich people have great water pressure.
管家先生
So, Jeeves,
能送我们回城里吗
any chance we can get a ride back to the city?
嗯  那我就...
Right. Well, I'll be in the...
去厨房了  布鲁斯少爷
in the kitchen, Master Bruce.
小姐
Miss.
他怎么回事
What's with him?
布鲁斯  怎么了
Bruce, what's going on?
我不回去了
I'm not going back.
什么
What?
我感激你教我的一切
I'm grateful for everything that you taught me.
但我该留在这儿
My place is here.
就这样吗
So, that's it?
-我不指望你理解  -是啊
- I don't expect you to understand. - Right.
因为你是布鲁斯·韦恩  我只是街头垃圾
'Cause you're Bruce Wayne and I'm street trash.
-塞琳娜  不是那样的  -就是
- Selina, it's not like that. - Yeah,
就是这样
it is.
It is.
没事的
It's fine.
祝你人生愉快  布鲁斯·韦恩
Have a great life, Bruce Wayne.
系统启动
System enabled.
小莱·汤普金斯医生
验尸官
汤普金斯
Thompkins.
喂
Hello?
你好  吉姆
Hi, Jim.